Guide to the Alex Harris photographs and papers, 1970-2015 RL.10060
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Project Files, 1970-2013 and undated, 17 boxes
  - South Africa: The Cordoned Heart, circa 1985-1986
    There are fifteen microcassettes and six audiocassettes in this group, arranged in order by last name, then by date. Unidentified tapes are at the end. Includes a set of four cassettes from a Cordoned Heart symposium, 1986. "MC" denotes microcassettes, "C," audiocassettes. Since the transcripts contain little or no reference to the tape numbering scheme, an individual transcript cannot be assumed to contain all appearances of an individual on various tapes. Transcripts are housed in the Correspondence Series under "South Africa--Transcripts."
    [Originals closed to use. Listening copy must be made. Please consult with a reference archivist before coming to use this item.]
    - Alberts, Paul (Sides A, B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_01)
      [Transcript available in Box 42. See also "Unidentified tapes" below.]
    - Alphers, Joseph (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_11)
      [Transcript available in Box 42.]
    - "Badsha at Duke" (Sides A and B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_C_019)
    - Badsha, Omar (Box 65)
      Badsha's name appears in numerous transcripts; no single transcript is filed under his name. He also appears on these microcassettes: MC_03; MC_04, (A and B); MC_06 (A and B) [plus "Jeewa"]; MC_07 (A and B); MC_10 (Side B); and MC_08 (A and B).
    - Barry, M. [Michael] (Side A), undated [1985] (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_12)
    - Berman, Bee (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_12)
    - Davies, Michael (Side A), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_03)
    - Gentry, Brenda (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_14)
    - Goldblatt, David--see "Unidentified tapes" below, undated (Box 65)
    - Johnson, Lisa (Side A), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_14)
    - Konings, Paul--see "Unidentified tapes" below, undated (Box 65)
    - Lawson, Lesley (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_09)
    - Ledechowski, Chris (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_03)
    - Ledechowski, Chris (Side A), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_05)
    - Lombard, Rashid (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_05)
    - Lombard, Rashid (Side A), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_12)
    - Lombard, Rashid (Sides A and B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_13)
    - Maclennan, Ben (Side A); Micro2, undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_01)
    - Maclennan, Ben (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_08)
    - Matthews, Jimmy (Side A), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_10)
    - Mendel, Gideon (Side A), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_08)
    - Mendel, Gideon (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_12)
    - Nunn, Cedric (Side A), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_02)
    - Payne, Bruce, and Alex Harris, "Bruce and Alex on S. Africa Duke Talk", undated (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_02)
    - Payne, Bruce, and Alex Harris, speaking on the Cordoned Heart project, undated (Box 27, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_15)
    - Perez, Bernie (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_01)
      [Transcript available?]
    - Peters, Myron, 1985 (Box 65)
      [Peters's name is not labeled on a tape, but a transcript is available in Box 42.]
    - South Africa: The Cordoned Heart Symposium, ICP [four audiocassettes labeled Side 1 -- Side 7], 1986 May 9 (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_C_020-C_023)
    - Sparks, Allister (sides A and B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_C_024)
    - Weinberg, Paul (A); see also "Unidentified tapes" below. (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_11)
    - W. [Weinberg], Paul (A and B); see also "Unidentified tapes" below. (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_04)
    - Unidentified: GBlatt [Goldblatt?] (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_02)
    - Unidentified: Paul [could mean Alberts, Konings, or Weinberg] (Side B), undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_05)
    - Unidentified: Side A may also refer to Goldblatt, undated (Box 65, Audio-cassette RL_10060_MC_09)
  - Other Projects
    - Notebook with "Bill Hawley" on cover (Director of Educational Programs in Public Policy at Duke Univ.) with notes on education programs in NC, and other loose notes on same, 1978 and undated (Box 62)
    - Red White Blue & God Bless You book mock-up, undated (Box 86)
    - Script from a talk concerning Harris's documentary film work (in partnership with Paula Erlich), The Time of Our lives: Living With Brain Cancer, circa 2012 (Box 62)
    - Various projects, 1984-2004 and undated (Box 80-81)
      Primarily slides related to various projects and individuals, material related to the Hart Fellows Program, and notes and slides for talks by Harris.
- Teaching Materials, 1976-2008 and undated, 5 boxes
  Syllabi, printed materials, student writings and slides, course evaluations, and other classroom materials for Harris's classes at University of North Carolina and Duke University. Arranged chronologically.
  [SOME MATERIALS MAY BE RESTRICTED: Students's grades and social security numbers have been redacted in all places where they were encountered. Any similar information remaining in the files is closed to use and must be removed.]
  - Classes at UNC and Duke, 1976-1996, 32 folders (Box 58-60)
  - Classes at Duke, 1997-2008 (Box 82-83)
  - Student Photographic Work, DOC, 2003-2004, 13 items (Box 61)
    Color photographs documenting North Carolina State Fairgrounds and Durham, North Carolina urban scenes, produced by three students taking Alex Harris's course, PPS/DOCST 177S, academic year 2003-2004. Consists of nine inkjet 9x13 inch color prints and four paper-format text panels, including the introductory text panel by Harris. Some of the students's work was exhibited in 2004 at the Center for Documentary Studies under the title Sense of Place. List of titles available in the box.
- Oversize Papers
  - Kwilecki, Paul: proofs and other documents from Kwilecki's photography book, Understandings (removed from Correspondence Series) (Box 61)
  - Printed materials and publicity, various projects, 1975-1991 and undated, 5 folders (Box 61)
  - Lyon, Danny, Memories of the Southern Civil Rights Movement, proofs, 1992, 4 folders (Box 61)
- Proof Prints, 1984-2015
  Comprises proof prints and general information for various projects, including Southern Color and the Gulf Coast and New Orleans Post Katrina.
  - Information folder, 2015 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Southern Color, 1984-1985 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Gulf Coast and New Orleans Post Katrina, 2006 (Box 73, Folder 3)